ithemes.com 2019-12-31

# Privacy Policy

**_ITHEMES PRIVACY POLICY_  
Effective August 5, 2019**

iThemes provides WordPress themes, plugins and software (“Services”). iThemes respects the privacy of every individual who visits www.ithemes.com (“Website”) and/or purchases its Services. This Privacy Policy is our commitment to transparency in communicating how iThemes collects, uses, and discloses the information that is collected from you, the visitor of its website and/or customer as well as the choices you have with respect to the information.

_**SCOPE OF POLICY**_

This Privacy Policy applies to how we collect, use, and disclose information from the following individuals:

  * **Customers** – individuals who register, on their own or on behalf of an entity, to use iThemes Services with the creation or administration of a iThemes account.
  * **Event/Marketing Participants** – individuals who provide their information to iThemes when they register for iThemes webinars, subscribe to marketing material, participate in surveys or contests, or attend other iThemes events.
  * **Website Visitors** – individuals who visit iThemes’ Website and opt to provide contact information including an email address to receive communications from iThemes. For purposes of this Privacy Policy, a Website Visitor does not include an individual who visits a website hosted by iThemes but owned and operated by an iThemes customer.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to a Customer’s website. Our Customers are responsible for the information they or their end users store in our hosting environment as well as compliance with applicable laws and regulations, and iThemes’ terms related to the collection and storage or personal information.

_**INFORMATION WE COLLECT**_

_Customers_  
iThemes asks for your account information which includes your name, business name, email address, physical address, phone number, credit card and bank account information (stored directly with a third party processor), and website domain. By voluntarily providing iThemes with your account information, you represent that you own and consent to our use of such personal data.

_Event/Marketing Participants_  
iThemes may ask for your name, email address, physical address, and phone number. Participation in events, surveys, contents, or subscribing to marketing material is voluntary and you may choose whether or not to participate and therefore disclose this personal data.

_Website Visitors_  
At your option, iThemes asks and may collect your name, email address, physical address, and phone number. In addition, we also collect information such as web server logs, internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, or other information as part of aggregated data.

iThemes uses cookies, beacons, tags, and other tracking technologies to gather demographic information about you, identify your visits to our Website, other interactions with our Website, and personalize your search experience on our Website. We gather information such as internet protocol (IP) addresses, internet service provider (ISP), operating system, browser type, date/time stamp, and store it in log files. To collect this information, a cookie, a standard feature of a website that allows us to store a small amount of data on your computer to allow our web servers to recognize you, may be set on your computer or device when you visit our Website. We may track your use across different websites and 2 Liquid Web d/b/a iThemes – Privacy Policy August 5, 2019 Version services. In some countries, including those in the European Economic Area (“EEA”), the information in this paragraph may be considered personal information under applicable data protection laws.

You can control how websites use cookies by changing your cookie settings (www.aboutcookies.org), but your modification may limit your use and functionality of some of the features on our Website. We may also use cookies and other tracking technologies to provide you advertising based on your browsing activities. You may opt out of targeted advertisements by visiting http://optout.networkadvertising.org, or if located in the EEA, you may opt out by visiting http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/.

_**HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION**_

iThemes uses the information it collects about you in the following ways:

  * To respond to any requests from you regarding sales and support.
  * To contact you regarding any agreements or accepted terms that you may have with iThemes for the Services.
  * To provide you with marketing emails, special offers, advertising campaigns, or newsletters.
  * To provide you with information logs associated with the use of iThemes’ Services.
  * To contact you regarding functionality changes to our Services or Website.
  * To develop new features and functionality to our Services and Website.
  * To collect payment and bill for our Services.
  * To help personalize searches.
  * To diagnose problems.
  * To find and prevent fraud.
  * To register your domain and IP address through ARIN (American Registry for Internet Numbers).
  * To carry out other purposes as disclosed to you through the Website, or found in terms or an agreement between you and iThemes.
  * Process for other purposes for which we obtain your consent.

_**HOW WE SHARE INFORMATION**_

iThemes shares the information it collects about you in the following ways:

  * Third Party Providers – iThemes may share your information with third party providers that provide services on our behalf. These companies may assist with marketing support, processing credit card payments, providing sales leads, and customer support. Third party providers may only process personal information pursuant to iThemes’ instructions, and in compliance with Privacy Policy and other applicable regulations (e.g. EU-US Privacy Shield framework).
  * _Advertising_ – Based on the cookies and other tracking devices, we may work with advertising companies to display ads that may be of interest to you
  * _Business Transactions_ – To provide information to a third party in the event of any disposition of all or any portion of our business (e.g. reorganization, sale, assignment, bankruptcy).
  * _Aggregated or De-identified Data_ – We may disclose or use aggregated or de-identified information with third party providers for research purposes relating to our Services.
  * _As Required by Law or Similar Investigations_ – To comply with legal obligations (e.g. subpoena) or investigate potential legal violations. Liquid Web may be required to share personal data in response to lawful requests from public authorities including to meet national security and/or law enforcement requirements.
  * _Safety_ – We may disclose your information to protect and defend the safety of iThemes in connection with investigating and preventing fraud or security issues.
  * _Consent_ – iThemes may share your information with your consent.

_**YOUR CHOICES**_

You may unsubscribe from receiving promotional or marketing emails from iThemes at any time by using the “unsubscribe” link in the email received, or by emailing us at privacy@ithemes.com. As outlined in the Section, Information We Collect, you can also control your cookie settings.

With respect to your account information, you may update, correct or delete information that you provided to us by logging into your iThemes account or contacting us at privacy@ithemes.com.

_**DATA RETENTION AND SECURITY**_

When iThemes no longer has a legitimate business need (e.g. termination of a Customer agreement) to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymize it.

iThemes takes all reasonable steps to protect information received from you from loss, misuse or unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and/or destruction. We maintain technical, physical, and administrative safeguards to secure your information, and we use industry standard Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption for your data that is transferred over the internet. Despite its use of encryption, iThemes cannot guarantee any method of transmission of information over the internet is 100% secure. If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, please contact us at privacy@ithemes.com.

_**LEGAL BASIS FOR PROCESSING PERSONAL INFORMATION**_

For individuals in the EEA, iThemes’ legal basis for collecting and using your personal information will depend on the personal information collected and the specific context in which we collect it. iThemes will process personal information from you where, a) we have your consent to do so, b) where processing is necessary for iThemes to perform Services pursuant to an agreement, or c) where processing is in our legitimate interests. and not overridden by your data protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms. In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect personal information, or may otherwise need the personal information to protect your vital interests or those of another person. At any time, you have the right to withdraw or decline consent. If you do not provide the requested information, iThemes will not be able to perform Services for you. Also, you have the right to object where we rely on our legitimate interests to process your personal information.

_**INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS**_

iThemes stores your information in the United States. iThemes may transfer your personal information to countries other than the country in which you live. Whenever iThemes transfers personal information originating from the EEA or Switzerland to other countries not deemed adequate under applicable data protection law, it will do so on the basis of the Privacy Shield Frameworks or EU Standard Contractual Clauses.

_**PRIVACY SHIELD**_

iThemes complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework regarding our collection, use, and retention of personal information from EEA countries and Switzerland transferred to the United States pursuant to Privacy Shield, as administered by the U.S. Department of Commerce. iThemes has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles with respect to such data. If there is any conflict between the terms in this Privacy Policy and the Privacy Shield Frameworks, the Privacy Shield Frameworks shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit https://www.privacyshield.gov/. With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Frameworks, iThemes is subject to the regulatory and enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission.

iThemes remains responsible and liable under the Privacy Shield Principles if third-party agents that it engages to process personal data on its behalf do so in a manner inconsistent with the Principles, unless iThemes proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, iThemes commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information transferred to the United States pursuant to Privacy Shield. European Union and Swiss individuals with Privacy Shield inquiries or complaints should first contact iThemes at the contact information in the “Contact Us” section below.

iThemes has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the Privacy Shield Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of 4 Liquid Web d/b/a iThemes – Privacy Policy August 5, 2019 Version your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit http://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/foreu-consumers for more information and to file a complaint. This service is provided free of charge to you.

If your Privacy Shield complaint cannot be resolved through the above channels, under certain conditions, you may invoke binding arbitration for some residual claims not resolved by other redress mechanisms. See Privacy Shield Annex 1 at https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction.

_**DATA SUBJECT RIGHTS**_

Individuals located in the EEA may have additional statutory rights available to them with respect to their personal information, including the right to access your personal information, have it erased, have it corrected, or object to or restrict processing. If you would like to make such a request, please email privacy@ithemes.com and we will respond within thirty (30) days. iThemes will need to verify that the individual is inquiring about his/her own information before we can assist with the request.

We will comply with such requests to the extent legally required by applicable law. For EU individuals, you also have the right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority.

_**CHILDREN**_

Our Website and/or Services is not directed at children and our services are designed for consumers and businesses. We do not knowingly collect information from or about children under 13 years of age, and use of our services by children under 13 years of age is forbidden.

_**CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY**_

iThemes reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, however, should we change the Privacy Policy in a material way, a notice will be posted on our website along with the updated Privacy Policy. If you disagree with the changes, you may terminate your Services.

_**CONTACT US**_

If you have any questions or concerns over this Privacy Policy, or wish to exercise any of your statutory rights, please contact us at:

iThemes Privacy Matters  
c/o Liquid Web, LLC  
Attn: Director of Security  
2703 Ena Drive  
Lansing, MI 48917  
USA  
Email – privacy@ithemes.com

Liquid Web d/b/a iThemes – Privacy Policy  
August 5, 2019 Version
